MAXIMILLIAN MANTEI

Doctoral Student

September 24, 1988

♦ Horner Weg 226, 22111 Hamburg, Germany

% https://www.maxmantei.com/

in max-mantei O maxmantei

+49 172 5279 304



EDUCATION

Doctoral Student in Economics

University of Hamburg, DFG Graduate School: Internationalization of the Law and its Economic Analysis

2016 - present

♥ Hamburg, Germany

MSc Politics, Economics, and Philosophy University of Hamburg

2013 - 2016

Grade: 1.3 (CGPA 3.7/4.0)

BA Political Science and Economics

University of Bremen

2009 - 2013

Bremen, Germany

Grade: 1.6 (CGPA 3.4/4.0) Erasmus Exchange Aarhus University

Aarhus, Denmark

Abitur

Freie Evangelische Bekenntnisschule Bremen

2006 - 2008

Premen, Germany

Grade: 1.3 (CGPA 3.7/4.0)

DISSERTATION WORK

Doctoral Thesis (DFG Scholarship)

The Law and Economics of Foreign Direct Investment

- Full Bayesian semi-parametric, hierarchical GLM estimation of FDI flows and stocks using dyadic panel data
- Causal models for endogenous sample selection and missing not at random data to estimate heterogeneous effects of treaty clauses

MSc Thesis

Declining Price Anomaly in Dutch Rose Auctions Revisited

- Replication study accounting for behavioural effects in Dutch auctions
- Hierarchical Bayesian analysis to model individual bidder behaviour

BA Thesis

Mechanical and Psychological Effects of Electoral Systems in Western-European Democracies in the Interwar Period

- Measuring the extend of strategic voting in merging democracies
- Non-linear Regression to quantify party (dis-)advantage due to district magnitude and heterogeneity

PROFILE

I'm a quantitative social scientist passionate about hierarchical Bayesian modeling, especially in Stan. I strongly believe in the interplay of domain expertise trough informed priors and quantification of uncertainty through probabilistic reasoning. I love exploring data, building bespoke models, and visualizing key insights.

TECHNICAL

R	••••
Stan	
Python	
Julia	
SQL	

SQL	••••
SKILLS	
Data Wrangling	••••
Statistical Modeling	••••
Machine Learning	••••
Data Visualization	••••
Dashboarding	••••

PACKAGES & TOOLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

Self-employed

Data analysis and statistical programming

🛗 Jan 2014 - present

Research Assistant

University of Hamburg

Faculty of Business Economics and Social Sciences

- Literature review for course work
- Formatting articles for journal submission

Research Assistant

University of Hamburg

DFG research project on distributional justice and procedures

Mov 2015 - Jul 2016

♥ Hamburg, Germany

- Conducting an behavioural economics RCT with real effort tasks
- Summarizing, visualizing, and analyzing collected experimental data

Research Assistant

Ruhr-Universität Bochum Chair of International Economics

di Oct 2014 - Sep 2016

♀ Bochum, Germany

- Compilation of an extensive dyadic panel dataset on foreign direct investments and confounding variables used in published research
- Conducting empirical analysis using gravity-type regression models

Tutor

Extracurricular tutorial: Social Choice and Welfare

m Sep 2014 - Mar 2014

Hamburg, Germany

Internship

HKM Gesellschaft für Marketingforschung & Beratung mbH

mar 2013 - Sep 2013

♀ Hamburg, Germany

- Data analysis with focus on the European automotive market
- Developing a methods guideline for practical application of factor models and regression analyses

Internship

Ministry of Economic and Labor Affairs Department of European Funds for Regional Development

Feb 2011 - Apr 2011

♦ Hamburg, Germany

• Quantification and evaluation of public disclosure measures

Internship

SPD Constituency Office Hamburg-Mitte

Aug 2009 - Sep 2009

• Organization and execution of campaign rallies during BTW2009

Compulsory Civilian Service

Senator for Education and Science

diam'd Aug 2008 - May 2009

Premen, Germany

 Assistance of physically and intellectually disabled children at an inclusive elementary school

LANGUAGES

German



English



Spanish



CONFERENCES

ETSG (Volume 14 Number 1)

20th Anniversary of the European Trade Study Group

♀ Bern, Switzerland

StanCon 2019

Cambridge University

Aug 2019

Cambridge, UK

StanCon 2018

Aalto University

AFED 2017

2nd Annual Conference of the French Association of Law and Economics

Mov 2017

♀ Aix-Marseille, France

SIDE 2017

13th Annual Conference of the Italian Society of Law and Economics

Rome, Italy

HOBBIES & OTHER

Stan Community Leader

Voluntarily supporting Stan users in statistical and computational issues https://discourse.mc-stan.org/

Music Enthusiast

Passionately listening to, playing, and creating music



Band Leader

Co-leading a group of over 20 musicians at our local church



Reading News

Interested in world politics, and current and historical affairs



Football Stats

Casually gathering, modeling, and visualizing football statistics